
"Swamp Front":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  exits:
    "Road to Southern Swamp": "true"
    "Tourist Information": "true"
    "Swamp Water Near Tourist": "can_swim_or_sink"
    "Swamp Near Potion Shop": "has(MASK_DEKU) || has_hover_boots" # Other cases accounted by the water path
    "Swamp Near Frog": "(event(SWAMP_OCTO_LEFT) || is_swamp_cleared) && (has(MASK_DEKU) || has_hover_boots || is_tall)"
    "Owl Swamp": "true"
  events:
    CLEAR_STATE_WOODFALL: "wisp_enabled(BOSS_ODOLWA, REMAINS_ODOLWA) || event(WISP_CLEAR_STATE_WOODFALL)"
    PICTURE_SWAMP: "has(PICTOGRAPH_BOX)"
    PICTURE_BIG_OCTO: "has(PICTOGRAPH_BOX) && soul_octorok"
    STICKS: "true"
    NUTS: "soul_deku_baba && (can_lift_bracelet || can_kill_baba_nuts)"
    RUPEES: "true"
    BOMBS_OR_BOMBCHU: "true"
    ARROWS: "true"
    MAGIC: "true"
    WATER: "true"
    FAIRY: "true"
    SWAMP_OCTO_LEFT: "is_swamp_poisoned && has_arrows"
    SWAMP_OCTO_RIGHT: "is_swamp_poisoned && has_arrows"
  locations:
    "Southern Swamp HP": "(has(DEED_LAND) && has(MASK_DEKU)) || (trick(MM_SOUTHERN_SWAMP_SCRUB_HP_GORON) && has_mask_goron) || short_hook_anywhere"
    "Southern Swamp Scrub Deed": "soul_business_scrub && has(DEED_LAND)"
    "Southern Swamp Scrub Shop": "soul_business_scrub && has(MASK_DEKU) && can_use_wallet(1)"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Front 01": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Front 02": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Front 03": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Front 04": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Front 05": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Front 06": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Front 07": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Front 08": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Front 09": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Front 10": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Front 11": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Front 12": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Rupee 1": "has(MASK_DEKU) || is_tall || short_hook_anywhere || has_hover_boots"
    "Southern Swamp Rupee 2": "has(MASK_DEKU) || is_tall || short_hook_anywhere || has_hover_boots"
    "Southern Swamp Hive": "is_swamp_poisoned && (has_mask_zora || can_use_deku_bubble || has_arrows || can_hookshot || ((is_adult || has_hover_boots) && (can_hookshot_short || (has_bombchu && trick(MM_HIVE_BOMBCHU)))))"


"Swamp Water Near Tourist":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  exits:
    "Swamp Front": "true"
    "Swamp Water Near Witch": "true"
    "Swamp Water Near Spider House": "is_swamp_cleared || has_mask_zora || (event(SWAMP_OCTO_RIGHT) && (can_use_nayru || is_tall))"
  events:
    SWAMP_OCTO_RIGHT: "is_swamp_poisoned && kill_big_octo_close"

"Swamp Water Near Witch":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  exits:
    "Swamp Near Potion Shop": "true"
    "Swamp Water Near Tourist": "true"
    "Swamp Water Near Frog": "is_swamp_cleared || has_mask_zora || (event(SWAMP_OCTO_LEFT) && (can_use_nayru || is_tall))"
  events:
    SWAMP_OCTO_LEFT: "is_swamp_poisoned && kill_big_octo_close"

"Swamp Water Near Frog":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  exits:
    "Swamp Water Near Witch": "is_swamp_cleared || has_mask_zora || (event(SWAMP_OCTO_LEFT) && (can_use_nayru || is_tall))"
    "Swamp Water Near Deku Palace": "is_swamp_cleared || is_tall || can_use_nayru"
  events:
    SWAMP_OCTO_LEFT: "is_swamp_poisoned && kill_big_octo_close"

"Swamp Water Near Deku Palace":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  exits:
    "Swamp Water Near Frog": "is_swamp_cleared || is_tall || can_use_nayru"
    "Swamp Water Near Spider House": "is_swamp_cleared || is_tall || can_use_nayru"
    "Swamp Back": "true"

"Swamp Water Near Spider House":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  exits:
    "Swamp Water Near Deku Palace": "is_swamp_cleared || is_tall || can_use_nayru"
    "Swamp Water Near Tourist": "is_swamp_cleared || has_mask_zora || (event(SWAMP_OCTO_RIGHT) && (can_use_nayru || has_mask_goron || is_tall))"
    "Near Swamp Spider House": "is_tall || can_use_nayru"
    "Near Swamp Grotto": "is_tall"
  events:
    SWAMP_OCTO_RIGHT: "is_swamp_poisoned && kill_big_octo_close"

"Swamp Near Frog":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  exits:
    "Swamp Front": "(event(SWAMP_OCTO_LEFT) || is_swamp_cleared) && (has(MASK_DEKU) || has_hover_boots || (is_tall && (can_use_nayru || is_swamp_cleared)))"
    "Swamp Back": "has(MASK_DEKU) || has_hover_boots || (is_tall && (can_use_nayru || is_swamp_cleared))"
    "Swamp Water Near Frog": "can_swim_or_sink"
  events:
    FROG_3: "has(MASK_DON_GERO)"
    SWAMP_OCTO_LEFT: "has_arrows"

"Swamp Near Potion Shop":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  exits:
    "Swamp Front": "has(MASK_DEKU) || has_hover_boots" # Other cases accounted by the water path
    "Swamp Water Near Witch": "can_swim_or_sink"
    "Swamp Potion Shop": "true"
    "Woods of Mystery": "true"
  locations:
    "Southern Swamp Pot 1": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Pot 2": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Pot 3": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 1 Grass 01": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 1 Grass 02": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 1 Grass 03": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 1 Grass 04": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 1 Grass 05": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 1 Grass 06": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 1 Grass 07": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 1 Grass 08": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 1 Grass 09": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 2 Grass 01": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 2 Grass 02": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 2 Grass 03": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 2 Grass 04": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 2 Grass 05": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 2 Grass 06": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 2 Grass 07": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 2 Grass 08": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch Pack 2 Grass 09": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch 1": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Near Witch 2": "true"
  gossip:
    "Southern Swamp Gossip": "true"

"Swamp Back":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  events:
    PICTURE_SWAMP: "has(PICTOGRAPH_BOX)"
    PICTURE_BIG_OCTO: "is_swamp_poisoned && has(PICTOGRAPH_BOX) && soul_octorok"
  exits:
    "Swamp Water Near Deku Palace": "is_swamp_cleared || is_tall || has_iron_boots || can_use_nayru"
    "Swamp Near Frog": "has(MASK_DEKU) || has_hover_boots || is_tall || has_iron_boots || (can_swim && can_use_nayru) || (is_swamp_cleared && can_swim)"
    "Deku Palace Front": "true"
    "Near Swamp Spider House": "has(MASK_DEKU) || is_tall || is_swamp_cleared || short_hook_anywhere || can_use_nayru || has_hover_boots"
    "Swamp Canopy Back": "(is_swamp_cleared && (can_swim_or_sink || is_tall || has_hover_boots || has_mask_goron || has(MASK_DEKU))) || short_hook_anywhere"
    "Swamp Canopy Front": "short_hook_anywhere"
  locations:
    "Southern Swamp Song of Soaring": "has_mask_zora && has_explosives && trick(MM_SOARING_ZORA)" # add adult to this trick?

"Near Swamp Spider House":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  exits:
    "Swamp Water Near Spider House": "is_tall || has_iron_boots || is_swamp_cleared || can_use_nayru"
    "Swamp Spider House": "has_sticks || has_arrows"
    "Swamp Back": "has(MASK_DEKU) || has_hover_boots"
    "Near Swamp Grotto": "has(MASK_DEKU) || short_hook_anywhere || has_hover_boots"
    "Swamp Canopy Front": "short_hook_anywhere"

"Near Swamp Grotto":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  events:
    MUSHROOM: "has(MASK_SCENTS)"
  exits:
    "Swamp Water Near Spider House": "is_tall || has_iron_boots || is_swamp_cleared || can_use_nayru"
    "Near Swamp Spider House": "has(MASK_DEKU) || can_hookshot_short || has_hover_boots"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto": "true"
    "Swamp Canopy Front": "short_hook_anywhere"

"Southern Swamp Grotto":
  region: ENTRANCE
  events:
    STICKS: "soul_deku_baba && (can_lift_bracelet || can_kill_baba_sticks)"
    NUTS: "soul_deku_baba && (can_lift_bracelet || can_kill_baba_nuts)"
    MAGIC: "true"
    RUPEES: "true"
    BOMBS_OR_BOMBCHU: "true"
    ARROWS: "true"
    FISH: "true"
    BUGS: "true"
    MUSHROOM: "has(MASK_SCENTS)"
  exits:
    "Near Swamp Grotto": "true"
  locations:
    "Southern Swamp Grotto": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 01": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 02": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 03": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 04": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 05": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 06": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 07": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 08": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 09": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 10": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 11": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 12": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 13": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grotto Grass 14": "true"

"Tourist Information":
  region: ENTRANCE
  exits:
    "Swamp Front": "true"
    "Boat Ride": "((soul_npc(SOUL_NPC_TOURIST_CENTER) && event(PICTURE_SWAMP)) || (event(KOUME) && (!setting(erIndoorsExtra) || can_use_wallet(1)))) && is_swamp_poisoned"
  locations:
    "Tourist Information Pictobox": "event(KOUME) && is_swamp_poisoned"
    "Tourist Information Boat Archery": "event(KOUME) && is_swamp_cleared"
    "Tourist Information Tingle Picture": "soul_npc(SOUL_NPC_TOURIST_CENTER) && (event(PICTURE_TINGLE) || event(PICTURE_DEKU_KING)) && is_swamp_poisoned"
#    "Tourist Information Big Octo Picture": "event(PICTURE_BIG_OCTO) && is_swamp_poisoned"
#    "Tourist Information Consolation Prize": "event(PICTURE_SWAMP) && is_swamp_poisoned"

"Boat Ride":
  region: NONE
  events:
    SWAMP_OCTO_LEFT: "true"
    SWAMP_OCTO_RIGHT: "true"
  exits:
    "Swamp Back": "true"

"Swamp Potion Shop":
  region: ENTRANCE
  exits:
    "Swamp Near Potion Shop": "true"
  locations:
    "Swamp Potion Shop Item 1": "soul_npc(SOUL_NPC_KOUME_KOTAKE) && has_mushroom && shop_price(0x0d) && (first_day || event(MEET_KOUME))"
    "Swamp Potion Shop Item 2": "soul_npc(SOUL_NPC_KOUME_KOTAKE) && shop_price(0x0e) && (first_day || event(MEET_KOUME))"
    "Swamp Potion Shop Item 3": "soul_npc(SOUL_NPC_KOUME_KOTAKE) && shop_price(0x0f) && (first_day || event(MEET_KOUME))"
    "Swamp Potion Shop Rupee": "true"

"Owl Swamp":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  exits:
    "Swamp Front": "can_reset_time"
  events:
    STICKS: "true"
    NUTS: "soul_deku_baba && (can_lift_bracelet || can_kill_baba_nuts)"
    FAIRY: "true"
    WATER: "true"
  locations:
    "Southern Swamp Owl Statue": "has_sticks || has_sword"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Owl 1": "true"
    "Southern Swamp Grass Owl 2": "true"

"Swamp Canopy Front":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  exits:
    "Swamp Water Near Deku Palace": "is_swamp_cleared || is_tall || has_iron_boots || can_use_nayru"
    "Swamp Back": "has(MASK_DEKU) || has_hover_boots"
    "Near Swamp Spider House": "short_hook_anywhere || has(MASK_DEKU) || has_hover_boots"
    "Near Swamp Grotto": "true"
    "Deku Palace Cliff": "true"
    "Swamp Canopy Back": "has(MASK_DEKU) || short_hook_anywhere"

"Swamp Canopy Back":
  region: SOUTHERN_SWAMP
  exits:
    "Swamp Back": "has(MASK_DEKU) || has_hover_boots"
    "Swamp Water Near Spider House": "is_tall || has_iron_boots || is_swamp_cleared || can_use_nayru"
    "Woodfall": "true"
    "Swamp Canopy Front": "short_hook_anywhere"
  locations:
    "Southern Swamp Song of Soaring": "has(MASK_DEKU) || short_hook_anywhere || (has_hover_boots && has_mask_bunny && (has_weapon || has_explosives) && trick(MM_SOARING_HOVERS)) || (has_mask_zora && has_explosives && trick(MM_SOARING_ZORA))"
